so now that we know that the cash is a
small memory insider processor where we
are trying to find the data before we go
to the main memory let's take some time
and recap what we need out of a cache we
need it to be fast which means it has to
be small because it's small not
everything will fit there will be a lot
of memory locations that we do not have
room for in our cache so when a
processor wants to access some memory we
can have a cache hit which occurs when
we find what we are looking for in the
cache the memory location we are
interested in was already brought from
the memory to the cache before so now we
are accessing it and we can just find it
in the cache and the access is then very
quick so this is what we want we want
fast accesses for most of our memory
accesses and that happens when we have a
lot of cache hits but because the cache
is very small and not everything fits in
it we can also have a cache miss this
happens when what we are looking for is
not in the cache and in that case we
have to access the slow memory when we
have a cache miss we want to copy this
location to the cache so that next time
we access it and hopefully we will
because of locality we will have a cache
hit so it is necessary to have cache
misses because that's how we really
bring stuff into the cache in order to
have hits the more locality we have the
more cache hits we will have and the
fewer cache misses because one miss will
bring the data into the cache and then
hopefully we will use it many many times
when we have a cache miss that is slow
that access is going to take some time
but that should happen very rarely most
of the time when we need something we
find it in the cache or at least we hope
to do that and we want to design our
caches so that that's how it works